Contact

kwamanebsn@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kwamane-liddell-jd-mha-bsn (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Leadership

Legal Writing

Time Management

Honors-Awards

St. Louis Business Journal's "30 under 30"

Scovel Richardson Scholarship Health Law Student of the Year

Kwamane D. Liddell, JD, MHA, BSN

Clinical and Administrative Operations Leader San Francisco, California

Summary

As a former trauma nurse in Chicago and St. Louis, Kwamane had a first-hand glimpse into how health disparities impact underserved communities. That exposure inspired his career goal which is to one day lead the delivery of health system services and advocate for those in need. Since then, he has gained additional experience as a house supervisor and furthered his education at Saint Louis University's top ranked Healthcare Law and Master of Health Administration Programs. While in St. Louis, Kwamane was also named one of the St. Louis Business Journal's 30 under 30 for his work in the community and healthcare.

He is currently an Administrative Fellow at Dignity Health where he works closely with the system's senior leadership team. Prior to that role, he was a house supervisor in a 190-bed acute care hospital where he acted as an administrative and clinical leader for the entire facility. That role expanded his experience to include the pharmacy, lab, radiology, surgery, and inpatient psychiatry. His previous clinical experience includes emergency services, critical care, and medical-surgical units. He is a Chicago native who loves food, travel, and sports but is still getting adjusted to all of the Warriors fans in San Francisco.

Experience

Alameda Health System Administrative Services Manager June 2020 - Present (2 months) Alameda, California, United States

Dignity Health
2 years
Director Of Business Operations
Page 1 of 4

August 2019 - June 2020 (11 months)

Sacramento, CA, United States

Operational, growth, and clinical leadership responsibility for outpatient infusion program, bariatric surgery service line, hyperbaric therapy program, and inpatient dialysis.

Administrative Fellow July 2018 - June 2020 (2 years) San Francisco Bay Area

St. Alexius Hospital House Supervisor March 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 5 months) Greater St. Louis Area

- On-site administrator of 190-bed hospital during assigned shift
- Supervise more than 90 nurses, patient care technicians, unit secretaries, and ancillary staff members
- Created automated sitter tracking system to calculate safe staffing ratios
- Operationalize quality improvement initiatives in clinical departments
- Manage interview process and disciplinary actions for clinical staff

Various Hospitals via Liquid Agents Medical Staffing Registered Nurse, Emergency Services June 2015 - July 2018 (3 years 2 months) Belleville, IL

- Led teams of two to four nurses to perform life-saving interventions on patients with traumatic injuries
- Communicated diagnoses to physicians while rapidly evaluating critical patients
- Coordinated the care of two to four high acuity patients

Ascension
Legal Extern
January 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)
Greater St. Louis Area

Johns Hopkins Medicine Administrative Intern - NAHSE Baltimore Chapter Summer Program June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months)

Baltimore, Maryland Area

Perioperative Services – Internal Float Pool

Identified \$550,000 waste in productivity from nurse turnover and development

Created foundational analyses for internal float pool for 70 operation rooms and 350 clinicians

Materials Management – Improved Productivity
 Improved standard work and eliminated 20 hours of wasted productivity per month

Improved workflow process that decreased crashed cart expiration by 60%

St. Louis Children's Hospital Administrative Intern February 2017 - May 2017 (4 months)

Greater St. Louis Area

- Developed cost-savings and cost-benefit analysis for MRI services that can save \$1.6 million per year
- Identified waste in hospital purchasing practices that can expedite purchases
- Learned operational structure in academic pediatric hospital with over 3,000 employees and 280 beds

Husch Blackwell Summer Associate May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months) Greater St. Louis Area

- Provided recommendations for health systems to improve patient care process and avoid risk
- Interacted with health systems to prepare responses for medical record audits
- Analyzed and updated physician service agreement
- Analyzed tax exemptions, limited liability laws, and various administrative opinions

Heartland Regional Medical Center 2 years 2 months

Registered Nurse, Emergency Services September 2014 - June 2015 (10 months) Marion, IL

- Performed systematic assessments and triages in 100-bed for-profit rural hospital
- Executed nursing role in emergency response systems
- Managed patient care processes in correlation with physician diagnoses

Patient Care Technician & Unit Secretary - Emergency Services December 2013 - September 2014 (10 months)

Marion, Illinois

- Assisted in emergency response protocols
- Obtained patient vital signs and electrocardiograms
- Supported nursing staff as they triage patients quickly and thoroughly

Certified Nurse Assistant & Unit Secretary May 2013 - December 2013 (8 months) Marion, Illionis

- Assisted patients with activities of daily living
- Communicated patient progress with nursing staff
- Input physician orders and stocked emergency department

Loyola University Medical Center Housekeeper March 2010 - August 2010 (6 months) Maywood, Illinois

- Navigated 519-bed academic medical center and responded to patient discharges
- Managed disinfection process for inpatient medical rooms
- Maintained patient, staff, and visitor safety while removing trash and linen from medical units

Education

Saint Louis University School of Law Juris Doctor (J.D.), Health Law/Healthcare Business/ Health Policy

Saint Louis University

Master's Degree, Health/Health Care Administration/Management

Southern Illinois University Edwardsville
Bachelor's Degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse